OF GIDEON DANIELS

PERSONAL DETAILS

FULL NAMES : Gideon Ashwin

 SURNAME
 : Daniels

 D.O.B
 : 07 / 09 /1996

 I.D
 : 960907 5272 087

 ADDRESS
 : 5 Crete Close

Eureka estate

7490

GENDER : Male

NATIONALITY : South Africa

HEALTH : Excellent

LANGUAGES : English, Afrikaans

ADMIRABLE QUALITIES : Attention to detail. Honest and Reliable. Outside the box thinker

CONTACT DETAILS

PHONE : 072 607 8261 / 068 324 3284

EMAIL : gideondaniels.dragoonix@gmail.com

SOCIAL MEDIA : FACEBOOK WHATSAPP INSTAGRAM LINKEDIN TWITTER

OBJECTIVE

Pride in the quality of my work, and a willingness to go the extra mile even if this means performing the most menial tasks to get the job done. I have the ability to plan strategically ensuring positive results and getting the job done on time. I am versatile, results-driven and beneficial to any company seeking to increase revenue. I would like to share my expertise and knowledge with colleagues that are as passionate about building ideas around the work area as I am. An organization that is forward thinking and able to challenge me on all levels, be it physically or mentally, will certainly appeal to me.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

INSTITUTION : Ravensmead Senior Secondary school

YEAR : 2014

QUALIFICATION : National Senior Certificate

INSTITUTION : Northlink College YEAR : 2016 – 2020

QUALIFICATION : N1- N5 Certificate and statement of results

EDUDCATIONAL GOALS

I want to complete my N6 qualifications in electrical engineering and finish my practical experience to qualify for a diploma as an electrical engineer. I also want to improve my matric mathematics and physics marks. My main goal is to study Computer Science one day.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

COMPANY : Jured installation Works CC

POSITION : Assistant to welders DURATION : DEC2015 – JAN2015

REFERENCE: Mervin Adams – 083 609 7330

COMPANY : Ster-Kinokor Parow

POSITION : Part Time Assistant Cashier
DURATION : 25 Feb 2018 – 30 August 2018

REFERENCE: MANDY – Regional Manager – 086 166 8437

PERSONAL PROFILE

VOLUNTEER AT YMCA RAVENSMEAD

POSITION : Mentor to children / Speaker / Assistant at events

DURATION : Since 2015 – Current

REFERENCE : William 081 546 4392/ 060 544 1975

I am volunteering at NPO's to help my communities and young people.....

SPORTS

- -Track runner
- -Cross country runner
- -Chess players
- -Soccer player
- -Table tennis player

I am inspired to experience the joy of other sports as well such as Basketball and Volleyball.....

HABITS & HOBBIES

- -Innovator (come up with ideas every day to help others)
- -Planner (plan schedules and ideas)
- -Gamer (Dota 2 & Albion online)
- -Bookworm (science-fiction & fantasy)
- -Skateboarder

I am building ideas and networks around businesses in my community via social media....

SKILLS

- -Leadership (awarded by high school)
- -Fast learner
- -Programmer (java and html css5 fundamentals)
- -Microsoft word & Excel fundamentals
- -Imaginative thinker (always come up with ideas)
- -First aid fundamentals (awarded By YMCA)

There are many skills I have yet to learn....

PERSONAL BUSINESSES

I do digital marketing and I am also a social media agent that promotes small businesses products and services on social media platforms such as Facebook, WhatsApp and Instagram. My business works flexible hours and won't affect any job opportunities given to me.

COVER LETTER

To whom it may concern

It is pleasure and privilege to be considered among many or few people for the job opportunity. I have no doubt that I am the best person for the job. I would like to start off by declaring that I am in no position to accept failure. My only goal is to be content and be successful in my attempts to get the job.

I have learned over the years that the only person that can define oneself is the person in the mirror. I am hardwired to think logically. My 12 years in school has taught me that emotions only give rise to failure and failure only gives rise to misery. To avoid such complications one must be diligent and focused at what he does. I have achieved many things during my 12 year period, from mathematics awards to being a leader among students. I have always had the unselfish behaviour to teach others who struggle with understanding the lessons.

After the hard lessons learned in school even harder lesson was awaiting me. My 3 years at college have proven that much. I had a choice to skip Electrical Engineering N1 but I remembered that it is important to learn the fundamentals. I began at N1 and finished until N3. During that time I became really good and even tutored my fellow peers at college. At times when you become good at something it can leave room for ignorance. I learned that the hard way. For the very first time I had failed a subject completely in N4. I did not know how to cope with failure and never gave up on trying passing again and again. Failure has taught me that no one will help you unless you help yourself. I passed N4 and eventually passed N5.

To this day those hard lessons have been hardwired into my mind. I have learned a lot from my failures and I have no intention to fail in the future. I declared at the beginning of this year that this is my year to compete and conquer. You ask why I am the best person for the job. It's because I have been through a lot of failures and have zero intention to fail again. One of my many goals for this year is to get a job and help serve my family and others who is in need of my services. "The ultimate measure of a man is not where he stands in moments of comfort and convenience, but where he stands at times of challenge and controversy.", a quote from Martin Luther King.

Kind Regard

Gideon Daniels